Guide to the Jonathan Huntting Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Jonathan Huntting Papers
1732-1860
RG 184
Yale University Divinity School Library
4
(8 boxes)
Collection consists primarily of manuscript sermons written by a Presbyterian clergyman in Long Island, New York. Jonathan Huntting (1778-1850) graduated from Yale College in 1804 and studied theology under Lyman Beecher. He was licensed to preach by the Presbytery of Long Island in 1805 and was minister first at Fishkill and then Southold from 1807 to 1828.
Huntting, Jonathan, 1778-1850
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from William Hedges, ca. 1980.
Biographical / Historical
According to Franklin Bowditch Dexter's Biographical Sketches of Graduates of Yale College, "Jonathan Huntting, youngest son of William and Puah (Osborn) Huntting, of East-Hampton, Long Island, and grandson of Nathaniel and Mary (Hedges) Huntting, of East-Hampton, was born on February 13, 1778. Jonathan Huntting (Yale 1735) was his great-uncle. He entered College after the opening the Sophomore year. After graduation he taught in the Academy in his native town, and in the meantime studied theology under the instruction of his pasto, the Rev. Dr. Lyman Beecher (Yale 1797), and the Rev. David S. Bogart, of Southhampton. He was licensed to preach by the Presbytery of Long Island on October 10, 1805, and supplied the pulpit in Fishkill for the first five months of 1806. In June, 1806, he began to preach in the Presbyterian Church in Southold, Long Island, where he was ordained and installed as pastor on August 20, 1807. On September 20, 1808, he married Julia, daughter of Abraham Sayre, of his native place. He fulfilled a long and useful ministry in Southold, until dismissed at his own request on August 27, 1828. He continued to reside there, but for much of the time served as stated supply to neighboring congregations. Thus, for the four years ending in the fall of 1832 he supplied the church on Shelter Island. He died at his home in Southold after ten days' illness, on December 30, 1850, in his 73rd year."
Scope and Contents
Series I is a sequence of dated sermons. The text of the sermon and the first date and place of delivery are noted in the finding aid. Series II contains less structured sermon notes and lectures, again in chronological sequence. Series III contains undated sermons, funeral service notes, and fragments of various sorts. Series IV contains materials not written by Huntting, primarily relating to the area of Long Island where he lived.
Arrangement
I. Dated Sermons, 1803-1842
II. Dated Sermon Notes, 1810-1832
III. Notes, Essays, Undated Sermons, 1802-1838
IV. Collected Material, 1732 - 1860
Sermons, American; Clergy; Huntting, Jonathan, 1778-1850
- Dated Sermons, 1803-1842; Series I
  - Hosea 8:12 Southhampton; Jeremiah 10.25 Fishkill, N.Y., 1803 Jan 25; 1804 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acts 26.28 Fishkill, N.Y., 1805 Dec 22 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - I Corinthians 4.7 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Jan 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - John 3.3 Cutchogue, N.Y., 1806 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Genesis 3.4-5 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Psalm 97.1 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Jan 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ecclesiastes 7.2 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - John 15.19 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Matthew 13.24-30, 1806 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ezekiel 36.37 Fishkill, N.Y., 1806 Mar 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Psalm 37.37 Fishkill, N. Y., 1806 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Romans 8.9 Oysterpond, N. Y., 1806 Jun 11 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Isaiah 55.6 Sterling, N. Y., 1806 Jun 12 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Revelation 14.13 Southampton, N. Y., 1806 Jun 15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hebrews 11.7 Fishkill, N. Y., 1806 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - II Corinthians 13.5 Cutchogue, N. Y.; Exodus 20:3 Southold, N.Y., 1806 Jul 11; 1806 Jul 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - John 3.3 Fishkill, N. Y., 1806 Jul 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Exodus 14.13 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hebrews 2.3 Fishkill, N. Y., 1806 Jul 21 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Song of Soloman Auguebogue, N. Y., 1806 Aug 7 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Numbers 24.17 Sterling, N. Y., 1806 Aug 7 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Isaiah 61.1-2 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Luke 10-15, 27 Sag Harbor, N. Y., 1806 Aug 15 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Galatians 5.19-21 Southold, N. Y.; 1 John 2:2 Southold, N.Y., 1806 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Numbers 10-29 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Aug 19 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Revelation 20.12 Fishkill, N. Y., 1806 Aug 25 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ecclesiastes 12.1 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Aug 31 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Proverbs 4 East Hampton, N. Y., 1806 Sep 7 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - John 3,10 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Sep 21 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Colossians 3.3 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Sep 28 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Deuteronomy 32.35 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Oct 26 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Matthew 11 Southold, N. Y.; Malachi 3:14, 1806 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Mark 15, 34 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Matthew 25 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Leviticus 10.3 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Ephesians Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 27 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Luke 6, 25 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 30 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 2 Peter 3, 14 Southold, N. Y.; Job 33:14 Southold, N. Y., 1806 Nov 30; 1806 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Psalm 89.15 Southold, N. Y., 1807 Jan 4 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Isaiah 57.12 Southold, N. Y., 1807 Jan 11 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Proverbs 21.2 Southold, N. Y., 1807 Jan 25 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Mark 13.37 Oysterpond, N. Y., 1807 Jan 28 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Galatians 3.26-29 Southold, N. Y.; Hosea 8:12, 1807 Feb 1 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Matthew 10.38 Southold, N. Y., 1807 Feb 8 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Galatians 3.26-27 Southold, N. Y., 1807 Feb 8 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Galatian 3.26-29 (Third Discourse) Southold, N. Y., 1807 Feb 15 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Lamentations 2.14 Southold, N. Y., 1807 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Ezra 8.22 Southold, N.Y., 1807 March 8 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Genesis 18.26 Southold, N. Y., 1807 March 15 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Genesis 9.14 Sag Harbor, N. Y., 1807 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Matthew 10.34-36 Shelter Island, N. Y., 1807 March 26 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Titus 1.15-16 Southold, N. Y., 1807 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Isaiah 52.3 Southold, N. Y., 1807 March 29 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - I Samuel 12.10 Southold, N. Y., 1807 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - John 15.21 Southold, N. Y.; Isaiah 3:11 Southold, N. Y., 1807 April 5 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - I Peter 2.2 Southold, N.Y., 1807 April 11 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Psalm 4.6 Southold, N. Y., 1807 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Matthew 3.10 Southold, N. Y., 1807 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Ephesians 5.16 Southold, N. Y., 1807 April 26 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Nahum 7.3 East Hampton, N.Y., 1807 May 22 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Isaiah 57.1 Sterling, N. Y., 1807 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Philippians 3.18-19 Southold, N. Y., 1807 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - John 14.23 Sag Harbor, N. Y., 1807 June 14 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - I Corinthians 1.21 Southold, N. Y., 1807 June 21 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Revelation 3.20 Sterling, N. Y., 1807 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Hebrews 12.1 South Island, N. Y., 1807 June 28 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - II Timothy 2.11 No location given; Zechariah 9:12, 1807 July 19 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Matthew 22.5 Smithtown, N. Y., 1807 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Hebrews 2.6 South Hampton, N. Y., 1807 July 26 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Job 9.4 No location given, 1807 Aug 2 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Malachi 3.16-18 Fishkill, N.Y., 1807 Aug 9 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - James 2.12 No location given; Psalm 102:16, 17, 1807 Aug 16; 1807 Aug 23 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Colossians 3.1 No location given, 1807 Aug 30 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Luke 16.34 No location given, 1807 Aug 16 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Isaiah 48.18 No location given, 1807 Sept 13 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - John 3.20 No location given, 1807 Aug 30 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - John 21.16 No location given, 1807 Sept 2 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Psalm 27.4 Sag Harbor, N.Y., 1807 June 7 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - II Corinthians 5.17 No location given, 1807 Sept 13 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Revelation 21.3-4 Northside, N.Y., 1807 Sept 16 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Ecclesiastes 3.12 No location given, 1807 Sept 27 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Luke 9.5-9 No location given, 1807 Sept 20 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Acts 16.31 Shelter Island, N.Y., 1807 Sept 20 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Genesis 3.9 No location given, 1807 Oct 4 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Zechariah 4.7 No location given, 1807 Sept 6 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Proverbs 4.7 Auguebogue, N.Y., 1807 Oct 11 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Psalm 27.14 No location given, 1807 Oct 25 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Luke 2.10 No location given, 1807 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - I Timothy 6.11 No location given, 1807 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Jonah 4 No location given, 1807 Nov 8 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Jeremiah 7.19 No location given, 1807 Nov 8 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Kings 18.21 No location given, 1807 Nov 15 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Psalm 107.21-22 No location given; Ezekiel 47:11, 1807 Nov 19; 1807 Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Hosea 10.12 No location given, 1807 Dec 6 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Matthew 16. 1-4 Southold, N.Y., 1807 Dec 6 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Titus 2.11-14 Southold, N.Y., 1807 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Romans 8.14 No location given, 1807 Dec 20 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Proverbs 17.15 No location given, 1807 Dec 20 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Revelation 21.7 No location given, 1807 Dec 27 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - I Samuel 16.7 No location given, 1807 Dec 27 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - James 4.14 No location given, 1808 Jan 1 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Psalm 69.4 No location given, 1808 Jan 10 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Luke 23.31 No location given, 1808 Jan 10 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - I Corinthians 9.27 No location given, 1808 Jan 31 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - II Corinthians 7.10 No location given, 1808 Feb 28 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - I Corinthians 1.28-29 No location given, 1808 March 14 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Lamentations 3. 39-41 No location given, 1808 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - John 12.35 Southold, N.Y., 1808 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Isaiah 42.16 No location given, 1808 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Galatians 3.1 No location given, 1808 April 3 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Joel 1.2 Oyster Pond, N.Y., 1808 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Ezekial 37.3 No location given, 1808 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Romans 14.19 No location given, 1808 May 1 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Jeremiah 6.14 No location given, 1808 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Psalm 10 No location given, 1808 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Luke 14.24 No location given, 1808 June 5 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Psalm 42.11 No location given, 1808 June 12 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Micah 4.5 No location given, 1808 June 25 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Proverbs 18.12 No location given, 1808 June 26 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - I Samuel 12.24 No location given, 1808 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Ecclesiastes 11.9 No location given, 1808 July 3 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - II Corinthians 10.18 No location given, 1808 July 10 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Job 25.4 No location given, 1808 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - I Samuel 24.5 No location given, 1808 July 17 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Psalm 141.5 No location given, 1808 July 31 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Psalm 100.15 No location given, 1808 Aug 21 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Isaiah 40.1 No location given, 1808 Sept (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - James 4.8 No location given, 1808 Sept 4 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Isaiah 59.12 No location given, 1808 Sept 8 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Ephesians 2.12 No location given, 1808 Sept 11 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Luke 13.25-28 No location given, 1808 Sept 17 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Proverbs 3.15 Southold, N.Y., 1808 Sept 28 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Psalm 119.10 No location given, 1808 Oct 2 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Psalm 77.3 No location given; Lamentations 1:16, 1808 Oct 9 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Amos 7.5 Oysterponds, N.Y., 1808 Oct 12 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Judges 10.14 No location given, 1808 Oct 30 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Proverbs 28.14 No location given, 1808 Oct 30 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - I Corinthians 1.17 No location given, 1808 Nov 6 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Matthew 6.10 No location given, 1808 Nov 6 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Exodus 32.36 No location given, 1808 Nov 27 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Psalm 2.11 No location given, 1808 Nov 24 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - John 12.43 No location given, 1808 Dec 1 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - John 14.6 Southold, N.Y., 1808 Dec 7 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Psalm 63:;1,2 No location given; Luke 2.11 No location given, 1808 Dec 11; 1808 Dec 25 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Hosea 13.9 No location given, 1808 Dec 25 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Galatians 6.14 No location given, 1809 Jan 1 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Luke 13. 6-9 No location given, 1809 Jan 1 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Matthew 5.16 No location given, 1809 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Isaiah 55. 8-9 No location given, 1809 Jan 30 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Jeremiah 8.9 / Joel 2. 15-17 No location given, 1809 March 16 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Luke 12. 20-21 Northside, 1809 March 20 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Job 15.20 No location given, 1809 March 26 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Matthew 22.22 No location given, 1809 April 2 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - I Corinthians 6. 19-20 No location given, 1809 April 2 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - II Kings 7.9 No location given, 1809 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Acts 17.31 No location given, 1809 April 9 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Amos 5.14 No location given, 1809 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Jeremiah 23.21-22 No location given, 1809 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Acts 13. 4-6 No location given, 1809 June 11 (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Psalm 90.14 No location given, 1809 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Deuteronomy 2.11 Shelter Island, 1809 June 25 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Deuteronomy 26.17 Shelter Island, N. Y., 1809 July 2 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Romans 6.20 South Hampton, N. Y., 1809 July 23 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Haggai 1, 2 No location given, 1809 Sept 21 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Luke 11.32 No location given, 1809 Aug 20 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - I John 2.6 Shelter Island, N. Y., 1809 Sept 3 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Proverbs 11.18 South Island, N. Y., 1809 Sept 10 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Proverbs 11.18 No location given, 1809 Sept 10 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Acts 2.37-38 Shelter Island, N. Y., 1809 Oct 11 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - II Corinthians 5.20 Middletown, N. Y., 1809 Oct 15 (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - I Corinthians 13.3 Cutchouge, N. Y., 1809 Nov 12 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Proverbs 2, 4, 5 Southampton, N. Y., 1809 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Romans 12.1 No location given, 1810 Jan 1 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - I Corinthians 5. 8 No location given, 1810 Jan 7 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Luke 10.42 No location given, 1810 Jan 7 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Revelation No location given, 1810 Jan 9 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Judges 5.23 No location given, 1810 Feb 18 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Matthew 5.20 No location given, 1810 Feb 25 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Psalm 81. 13-14 No location given, 1810 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Isaiah 1.16 No location given, 1810 March 22 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Isaiah 61.1 No location given, 1810 April 15 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Luke 23.28 No location - funeral of Calvin Wells, 1810 April 29 (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Exodus 20.3 No location given, 1810 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Galatians 4.15 No location given, 1810 Feb 25 (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - John 7.49 No location given, 1810 July 29 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Philippians 3.10 No location given, 1810 Aug 5 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Exodus 20.3 No location given, 1810 Aug 5 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Luke 17.10 No location given, 1810 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Acts 24.15 No location given, 1810 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Exodus 20. 4-6 No location given, 1810 Sept 30 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Hosea 9.1 No location given, 1810 Nov 22 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Exodus 20. 4-6 No location given, 1811 April 28 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Job 17.15 Sermon notes, 1812 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Psalm 79.42 No location given, 1812 Nov 26 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Ephesians 2.13 Sermon notes 9, 1811 April 7 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Hebrews 11.8 No location given, 1811 April 29 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Deuteronomy 30.19 No location given, 1811 July 27 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Isaiah 28.13 Auguebogue, N.Y., 1812, Aug 9 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Colossians 4.17 No location - ordination sermon, 1814 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Romans 8.16 Southampton, N.Y., 1814 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Jeremiah 36.31 Northside, N. Y.; Matthew 4:10 No location, 1816 May 29; 1816 Dec 15 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Haggai 2.15 No location given, 1818 Jan 4 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Romans 3.27, etc. Nogneck, N. Y. Lectures, 1818 March 10 - 1821 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Daniel 4.24-25 No location given, 1818 June 21 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Acts 26.27 Newtown, N. Y., 1819 Aug 29 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Fast Subjects - Notebook No. 2, 1821 Aug 16 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Philippians 4.3 No location given, 1822 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Acts 17.4 No location given; I John 5:9-12, 1823 March 12; 1823 Jun 22 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Proverbs 31.30 No location given, 1824 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Psalm 62.8 No location given, 1824 Dec 5 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Acts 16.13 No location given, 1825 March 23 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - John 6.63 No location given, 1825 April 10 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Psalm 28.7 No location given, 1826 Jan 10 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Isaiah 53.5 No location given, 1826 June 4 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Ezekiel 33.9 No location given, 1826 June 18 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Luke 10. 10-12 No location given, 1826 July 25 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - I Corinthians 3.18 No location given, 1826 Oct 29 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Isaiah 46.8 No location given, 1827 March 29 (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Deuteronomy 5.33 No location given, 1828 March 27 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Notes - various passages No location given, 1827 Sept 23 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Psalm 122.6 No location given, 1827 May 20 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - I Samuel 2.13 No location given, 1827 Sept 2 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Ephesians 2.16/I Timothy 115 No location given, 1828 Jan (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - I Corinthians 6.9 Easthampton, N.Y., 1828 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Matthew 21.42 Cutchogue, N.Y., 1828 May 2 (Box 5, Folder 225)
  - Proverbs 9.6 No location given, 1828 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Romans 7. 8-9 No location given, 1828 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 227)
  - Luke 22.19 No location given, 1828 June 1 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Amos 6.1 No location given, 1828 July 20 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - I Thessalonians No location given, 1828 Aug 24 (Box 5, Folder 230)
  - Deuteronomy 11.19 No location given, 1829 Oct 14 (Box 5, Folder 231)
  - Psalm 46.8 No location given, 1830 Jan 6 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Matthew 6.21 Shelter Island, N.Y., 1830 Jan 17 (Box 5, Folder 233)
  - Malachi 3.2 Shelter Island, N.Y., 1830 Oct 31 (Box 5, Folder 234)
  - Job 21.30 No location given, 1831 July 9 (Box 5, Folder 235)
  - I Peter 1.16 Shelter Island, N.Y., 1831 Oct 7 (Box 5, Folder 236)
  - Proverbs 20.1 Oysterponds, N.Y., 1833 Feb 26 (Box 5, Folder 237)
  - Psalm 144.15 Southampton, N.Y., 1834 April 15 (Box 5, Folder 238)
  - Titus 3.1 West Hampton, N.Y., 1836 April 19 (Box 5, Folder 239)
  - John 3.7 Southold, N.Y., 1836 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 240)
  - Mark 13.36 Southold, N.Y., 1836 May 22 (Box 5, Folder 241)
  - Psalm 92.13 No location given, 1836 Dec 4 (Box 5, Folder 242)
  - Romans 14.7 No location given, 1837 Jan 2 (Box 5, Folder 243)
  - Isaiah 48.17 No location - funeral of child of A. Overton, 1837 Sept 22 (Box 5, Folder 244)
  - Genesis 6.22 Franklinville, N.Y., 1838 Nov 4 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Daniel 5.27 No location given, 1839 Jan 11 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Luke 14.18 Nashamanock, N.Y., 1840 Aug 16 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Isaiah 32. 14-15 No location given, 1841 May 16 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Genesis 18.25 No location given, 1842 Nov 14 (Box 5, Folder 249)
- Dated Sermons Notes, 1810-1832; Series II
  - Sermon Notes 2 Southold, N. Y., 1810-1813 (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - No. 3 Preparatory Lectures No location given, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - No. 4 Preparatory Lectures Franklinsville, N. Y., 4 April 1823- 3 June 1825 (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Sermon Notes No. 10 No location given, 1811 (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Sermon Notes No. 14 No location given, 24 May - 26 June 1812 (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Sermon Notes No. 15 No location given, 2 Aug - Sept 20 1812 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Sermon Notes No. 16 Various locations, 27 Sept - 27 Dec 1812 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Sermon Notes No. 17 Various locations, 1 Jan -14 March 1813 (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Sermon Notes No. 18 Various locations, 18 March -9 May 1813 (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Sermon Notes No. 19 Various locations, 9 May - 5 Sept 1813 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Sermon Notes No. 20 Various locations, 5 Sept - Oct 24 1813 (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Sermon Notes No. 21 Various locations, 31 Oct - 13 Feb 1814 (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Sermon Notes No. 22 Various locations, 20 Feb - 29 May 1814 (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Sermon Notes No. 23 Various locations, 5 June 1814 - 6 Nov 1814 (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Sermon Notes No. 24 Various locations, 6 Nov 1814- March 16 1815 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Sermon Notes No. 25 Various locations, 19 March - 14 May 1815 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Sermon Notes No. 26 Various locations, 14 May - Sept 3 1815 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Sermon Notes No. 27 Various locations, 10 Sept - Dec 3 1815 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Sermon Notes No. 29 Various locations, 30 June - 8 Dec 1816 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Sermon Notes No. 30 Various locations, 7 Jan - 23 June 1816 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Sermon Notes No. 31 Various locations, 11 May - 12 Oct 1817 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Sermon Notes No. 32 Various locations, 17 Oct 1817- 3 May 1818 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Sermon Notes No. 34 Various locations, 29 Nov 1818- 2 May 1819 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Sermon Notes No. 35 Various locations, 9 May - 28 Nov 1819 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Sermon Notes No. 32 Various locations, 14 June 1818 - 20 Dec 1818 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Sermon Notes No. 38 Various locations, 18 Dec 1820 - 9 Sept 1821 (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Sermon Notes No. 39 Various locations, 28 Oct 1821 - 14 July 1822 (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - Sermon Notes No. 40 Various locations, 14 July 1822 - 6 April 1823 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 41 Various locations, 13 April 1823- 23 Nov 1823 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 42 Various locations, 30 Nov 1823 - 30 May 1824 (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 43 Various locations, 6 June 1824 - 21 Nov 1824 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 44 Various locations, 5 Dec 1824 - 26 June 1825 (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 46 Various locations, 3 July 1825 - 15 Jan 1826 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 47 Various locations, 29 Jan - 25 June 1826 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 48 Various locations, 9 July 1826 - 4 March 1827 (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 49 (Romans 3.19) Various locations, 1 April 1817 (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Sermon Notebook No. 50 Various locations, 14 Oct 1827 - 22 July 1832 (Box 6, Folder 286)
- Notes, Essays, Undated Sermons, 1802-1838; Series III
  - Psalm 119, 140 Nogneck, N. Y., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 287)
  - Sermon extracts No location given, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 288)
  - Isaiah 42.23- 25; Eccl. 11:9; Leviticus 10:3 No location given, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 289)
  - Isaiah 6. 5; Isaiah 60:7 No location given, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 290)
  - Zachariah 9. 12, Sermon Notes No location given, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 291)
  - Fragments No location given, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 292)